But as it has fallen out, we look at -
Those who have the lowest resting heart rate and then you are somewhere -
between 35 and 60 beats per minute.
And then compared to those who have high resting hearts -
And then you are up to 85 to 140-145 beats per minute.
Right.
Then I also think spontaneously that you have taken into account -
These well -trained people.
I heard that ...
On TV4 yesterday, they referred to Gunde Svan.
He's - after all -
Known for its low resting pulse, but ...
... These are factors that you have counted on then?
Yes exactly.
Because we know that affects, just as you say.
If anyone loses anything in the floor that we are not prepared for, -
And it melts loudly, then comes our brain -
automatically orientate us against the sound.
We will register the event -
And then we will also be affected in our body by this.
We are afraid that there is something we have not prepared for.
So we might start to sweat a little in our hands.
The pulse might go up a bit -
And we react physiologically to what is happening outside us.
- Right.
It can be said to be psychophysiology.
So the joint between the brain, body and what is happening around us.
Right.
And how is this related to your study?
Vilacule is a psychophysiological ... a psychophysiological measure.
We think that resting heart rate ...
When we talk about resting hearts, you might think of that -
“I lie and rest, we measure the pulse.
I am calm and at home in my sofa. ” -
Or "I lie in bed and just take it easy".
So it is not really with the resting heart rate -
As we think about it in a research context, -
But then we think about it as a situation there ...
... the person who gets his heart rate measured -
is perhaps in a hospital environment or in a pattern environment -
Or in a lab environment, or wherever you are.
An environment that is not at home.
Someone else measures the pulse on one.
So it's a pretty strange situation in many ways.
So that's why we think that then you should react a little -
On this stimuli that is around us, that we become ...
... maybe nervous or that we think it's unpleasant -
Or yes, a little stressed you are theoretically in such a situation.
the assessment for relapse, -
Just because it is quite specific with low resting hearts, -
Too low resting heart rate is associated with antisocial behavior, -
While high resting heart rate is assisted with many other things.
So it is not as specific with high resting heart rate as it is with low resting heart rate.
Therefore, it becomes an appealing factor to include in the equation.
And it is also relatively easy to measure, -
It is not invasive in any way, but it is ...
One can count the pulse in a very simple way -
And it also makes it appealing.
Yes, just because then my next question also becomes: What do we do now?
What do you do now with this knowledge and with this one -
The discovery, so to speak?
What is the next step in this?
Yes, the next step, what I am doing and do, that I am curious about ...
Now we know that this applies to men, -
And most studies have been predominantly on men -
Just because we know that men are over -represented in -
Crime statistics, we have a hard time coming out.
But there are also indications that low resting hearts -
Can also increase the risk of committing crimes in women.
So I really want to continue to investigate it -
and see if we see similar associations -
between resting and crime in women.
than women because they have a lower resting heart rate?
I'll just say that, that you have to ask questions in the chat here -
To Sofi if you come on something during the way.
Now we have talked for about a quarter.
But I also think it is important to study such studies -
And this kind of research will benefit society in some way.
And this might be a huge question to one like you, -
But where do you see this taking us, say in 10 years, -
What have we done to this study and this type of research then?
Yes, so as I would describe psychophysiological research, -
So I would say that it is primarily basic research.
For example, if one has anxiety or phobias -
So maybe in a lab environment you will be exposed to what you are afraid of -
While seeing how to react in the body, -
and then by practicing handling the feeling and reaction in the body -
So you can learn to control this a little neighbor.
So it's definitely an appealing thought.
Could this be something that can be applied to resting heart rate and crime?
I don't know, but ... - But maybe you know in a few years.
In 10 years we may know a little more.
- Yes, but exactly.
But if I'm sitting at home now watching this call -
And I have low resting hearts, I need to be afraid that I -
will commit any crimes, right?
No I do not think so.
This with the association between low pulse and crime -
Is at group level.
And i usually see -
When I talk about this for students, that many are sneaking down -
And take the pulse of themselves while I talk.
But no, it's not at the individual level, but we see it at group level -
And of course, many have low resting hearts -
that will never commit crimes.
Maybe you are looking for some other type of kick, possibly, -
But it is not that one will commit crimes -